It's morning, Big Brother. Time to get up.
You go on without me.
I'm tired from battle and I want to sleep.
No can do.
I have to comb and tie your hair back.
And if you don't get up,
Father will just keep nuzzling you.
I'll get up.
How pretty. Even after an intense battle,
it's not damaged.
You received the name "Tokiyuki"
during your genpuku ceremony,
but you never cut your hair
as part of becoming an adult, did you?
Because all the important retainers
told me not to cut it just yet.
My brother never listened
and went and cut his own hair anyway.
It's so annoying to maintain.
Was he not supposed to?
Long hair is a symbol
of good luck, Shizuku.
Good luck?
Hair that has never been cut
represents purity.
Children are said to possess holy powers,
and a child whose hair has never been cut
is the absolute embodiment
of all that is auspicious.
Which is why I have left your hair uncut.
Warriors are particularly drawn
to anything
that brings them good luck
on the battlefield.
A child with such long, luxurious hair
leading an army
is sure to strengthen warriors' hearts.
But if you are to
become the lord of the realm,
you cannot remain
with a child's long hair forever.
Lord Tokiyuki.
If you do manage to reclaim the throne…
Um…
Would it be all right if I cut your hair?
Of course.
If he cuts my hair, that would make him
my eboshi-oya. My genpuku sponsor.
I don't really mind either way.
At times, it feels like
he has me in the palm of his hand.
He can be selfish,
and somewhat of a dictator.
He's annoying
when he tells me to "Study, study, study."
He does hold me in his arms sometimes.
And at times, he'd drop everything
and come to rescue me.
I see.
At some point, I…
Ouch!
Hey, you. Don't let
all this special treatment
go to your head
just because you're a Hojo kid.
They made me a god.
That means I'm better than you.
Oh, my. Lord Tokiyuki.
My apologies
for not being able to visit more often.
SON OF YORISHIGE SUWA
TOKITSUGU SUWA
Mr. Tokitsugu. It's been a while.
I take it this is your first time
meeting my son? This is Yoritsugu.
What's the matter, Yoritsugu?
Have you introduced yourself yet?
Yes, Father dear.
I was so nervous because I finally got to
meet Lord Tokiyuki, whom I admire so much.
I just blurted out a greeting,
and I think I startled him a little.
I must have startled him a little.
Where are your manners?
Please forgive him, Lord Tokiyuki.
Come! Let's go see Grandpapa together!
I was shocked when I heard that
Mr. Yorishige had a grandson, but…
What does he mean they "made him a god"?
Actually, before that…
GRANDSON OF YORISHIGE SUWA
YORITSUGU SUWA
Let's get this straight once and for all.
A god versus the Hojo… Who outranks who?
He's a grouch! He's a cantankerous,
crusty, little grouch!
THE ELUSIVE SAMURAI
TWO YEARS AGO
You're so cute, Yoritsugu!
One day you will inherit all of Suwa
and become a marvelous god!
Until two years ago, I was destined
to be the leading figure of Suwa's future.
It's the Hojo child!
The young Hojo lord
has escaped and made his way to us!
Oh, the poor Young Lord!
Come, Lord Yoritsugu.
Let's go and welcome the Young Lord.
I'm… fine.
You made it!
You've traveled a long way.
You must be tired.
I've prepared a meal for you.
Come. This way.
Young Lord! Quickly! This way!
You're passing on your role as a god?
That's right.
I've already left most of
my duties as a god to my son, Tokitsugu.
But I'd like to consolidate everything
under my grandson, Yoritsugu, instead.
So that's what he meant when he said
they "made him a god."
To think…
such a young child inheriting such a role…
You left yourself wide open!
That doesn't mean you should nuzzle me!
He gets bigger and better nuzzles
than I ever got.
And why do you get to sit next to
Grandpapa anyway?
That should be my spot!
Well then, Mr. Yorishige.
I think I'll be off for now.
Don't be so quick to run away.
You'll make me sad.
Just a little more?
Please stop pawing all over me!
He gets more aggressive pawing and tickles
than I ever got.
Why do you get to hog Grandpapa's love?
First, I must open
Grandpapa's eyes to reality.
THUD
Well, Lord Tokiyuki,
I'd like us
to get to know each other more.
Please make me your favorite!
Lord Tokiyuki! What have you done?
No, I… He just…
He was the same when we met earlier.
I don't think
Lord Tokiyuki likes me very much…
When I went to introduce myself,
he grabbed me by the collar…
I'm a Hojo.
There is no one in Suwa above me.
Face me in a showdown tomorrow.
The loser will be exiled.
That's what he said to me. I didn't
want to, but I accepted his challenge.
Lord Tokiyuki! I had no idea
you've been hiding such a menacing side!
Lord Tokiyuki. Apologize. Apologize, now!
Hey! In what world
would I ever say something like that?
There's more.
Someday, I'm going to kill that Yorishige.
The way he shines so bright
is such an eyesore.
He said.
That is terrible.
Lord Tokiyuki. Apologize. To me.
I would never say that!
And who was that supposed to be?
But it's okay. Lord Tokiyuki is
the last shining light of the Hojo.
If I must be exiled, there could be
no greater honor
than to receive his judgment.
And so, Lord Tokiyuki,
I will see you tomorrow for our showdown.
Don't you dare run away.
I will see to it that
you never set foot in these lands again.
Good grief. You know it's not nice
to go around threatening children.
Right, Lord Tokiyuki?
Please.
I beg your forgiveness, Lord Tokiyuki.
Yoritsugu must also be at fault here.
After all, he can be rather ignorant
to the ways of the world.
Yes. That's right. Y-Yes, exactly.
Let's just let this slide on both sides.
You two. Sit down.
You do know he was lying just now, right?
Yes.
And you do know that
my poor thigh took the brunt of it?
We were feigning ignorance.
As a freeloader,
I know that I'm encroaching on his space.
In fact, I feel sorry for Yoritsugu.
However,
and I hope you can forgive my forwardness,
but if his precious father and grandfather
continue to tolerate such behavior,
don't you think he'll grow up
to become the sort of god
who wouldn't hesitate
to bring people down?
Please forgive our lack of manners.
We are truly ashamed.
We feel… guilty
when it comes to the child.
Guilty?
For the sake
of his father and grandfather,
he has been made to shoulder
such a heavy burden
and at such a young age.
Should the Arahitogami fall in battle,
the entirety of Suwa Grand Shrine
would cease to exist.
As my father and I are to join
the great war, we must entrust Yoritsugu,
who has no involvement
in the fighting, with the role of god.
I see. So that's why he had to become
a god at such a young age.
But it is as you say, Lord Tokiyuki.
As it stands, we are not setting him up
for a good future.
In fact, he may
be taking his destiny too seriously.
He acts sweet for us,
but he no longer lets on
to anyone how he truly feels about things.
And now, he is showing his true feelings,
his hatred, to you, and you alone.
This could be the perfect opportunity.
Please go out there
and handle this showdown well.
Please become the kind of friend
he feels he can open up to.
You irresponsible parents!
That said, I still am partly to blame.
I'll do my best to get along with him.
We may be calling it a showdown.
But really,
we're just two kids playing games.
That should give us the opportunity
to open up to one another.
THE NEXT DAY
GOOD LUCK, LORD YORITSUGU
He's really out for a fight!
I told you. I am a god.
One word from me, and the entirety
of Suwa Grand Shrine will bend to my will.
I'm impressed
you decided to show up, Tokiyuki.
Our showdown will be a game of tag.
And you're "It."
My goal will be the Holy Pillar.
If you can't catch me
before I get to it, I win.
You will pack your things and leave.
Yoritsugu.
I just want to get along with you.
And if we're going to play a game of tag,
I must say,
I'm going to be faster than you…
I don't want to hear it!
The game starts now!
What?
Ugh… Fine.
Mr. Moritaka?
I'm not sure I understand
the circumstances, Lord Tokiyuki,
but do forgive me.
Lord Yoritsugu says if I don't stop you,
there will be divine punishment.
This is the power of an Arahitogami.
They all do exactly as I say.
A human is no match for a god, Tokiyuki!
Well then, dear god.
I might need to teach you a little lesson.
Young Lord! Prepare yourself!
Huh?
He's escaped that way! Stop him!
Compared to the hundred
I went up against before,
this is no problem at all.
If you want to stop me,
you'd better bring arrows or Sadamune!
There really is no stopping him.
You wouldn't guess it by looking at him,
but he's survived many battles,
though never officially.
Meanwhile,
-Lord Yoritsugu has only just become god.
-What?
Those doing his bidding are mostly
civilians who have never seen combat.
There's no way they can stop him.
No way! How did you do that so easily?
How did he get past all of us?
All right.
It's just you and me now, Yoritsugu.
Huh? Oh, my gosh, oh, my gosh,
oh, my gosh! Why is he so excited?
But I've been walking the grounds of Suwa
Grand Shrine from the moment I was born.
You've only been living here
for less than two years.
I am far more familiar
with the terrain than you!
Now, he'll have to take a big detour.
I will reach the Holy Pillar
before he does.
The Holy Pillar is still a long way off.
Would you like to keep going, Yoritsugu?
What is with you?
I thought
you were only good at running away.
Since when were you good at chasing too?
I guess I just get a burst of energy
when I'm chasing while being chased.
And I know that nobody needs
to get hurt in this situation.
So I can just let loose
and have fun with it.
But going forward,
I must become a symbol of war,
knowing that it means hurting people.
If I am exiled, you may have to step up
to that role instead.
You and I are both destined
to become symbols at a very young age.
But I think you can wait a little longer
before you start hurting people.
You think you're so high and mighty!
This showdown's not over ye--
Yoritsugu!
I need to find something for him to grab.
I need to be quick, or it'll be too late!
-Grab on!
-Huh?
Owie owie owie!
You idiot! You're gonna rip your hair!
It's fine! Just hurry up and climb!
If your hair rips,
you won't be seen as pure!
You'll lose your prestige
among the people!
You're growing yours out
for the same reason as me!
The only symbol of purity we need is you!
You are a Suwa, and I am a Hojo.
After all, my destiny lies
on the battlefield and nowhere else.
Please hurry! My neck's about to snap!
You're an idiot.
If you'd let me die, you would have had
one less burden to deal with.
I wanted to be your friend.
But more than anything,
I don't want to make Mr. Yorishige sad.
Mr. Yorishige is like a father to me,
but it's no match
for the familial bond that you two share.
Ever since you arrived,
Grandpapa's been having
more and more meetings
with Shinano warriors that
I've never met before.
He doesn't visit me as much as he used to.
I don't even care about being a god.
I just don't want anyone
stealing my grandpapa away from me.
I see. Mr. Yorishige's been too busy
for Yoritsugu ever since the war started.
All right then.
Leave it with me, Yoritsugu.
Huh?
I am your father and
your grandfather's lord, after all.
I can ask them to indulge me
once in a while.
Which is why, Mr. Yorishige,
I have ordered Mr. Tokitsugu
to handle all duties as head of Suwa
on his own for the next three days.
And I command you, Mr. Yorishige,
to dote on your grandson
for the next three days.
Please don't let him feel lonely anymore.
Now, Mr. Yorishige is all yours
for the next three days.
Make him dote on you as much as you like.
Tokiyuki?
I see.
So you've been feeling lonely, Yoritsugu.
And you're right. I haven't been paying
much attention to you lately.
RUB RUB RUB RUB RUB RUB RUB
Why didn't you say so sooner?
I'm gonna love you
with all my heart, body, and soul.
Rub rub rub rub rub…
That hurts. His aged cheek is hurting me.
Yorishige's aging skin is as rough
as 1,500 grit sandpaper.
While a few minutes of nuzzling
would normally be harmless,
three days and three nights of continuous
nuzzling would cause skin to split,
flesh to tear, and bone to sand.
Yorishige himself has something akin
to divine protection.
He suffers zero damage.
And hey, just because I don't want
anyone stealing my grandpapa away from me
doesn't mean I'm a fan of nuzzling.
In fact, I even get sick of him
when it's just the two of us all the time.
Wait… Is this all he's gonna do
for the next three days?
I must do as Lord Tokiyuki commands.
Get ready for a million cheek rubs
over the next three days!
No!
SCREEEEEEECH
Hey, Young Lord. What's up?
You seem to be in a good mood.
ZERO MALICE
Kojiro. It feels good
knowing you've done a good deed.
Huh?
THE END
I'll get you for this, Tokiyuki.
Yoritsugu Suwa was seven at this time.
He went on to become
one of Tokiyuki's greatest comrades.
What's with that samurai?
Yeah. He looks really motivated.
It's almost like he's got the words
"let's do this" written on his face.
Now, I wonder
if Lord Tokiyuki is doing well?
LET'S DO THIS
TOKIYUKI'S UNCLE
YASUIE HOJO
Let's go!
EPISODE 15 (1335) - TOKIYUKI
AND THE THREE GREAT GENERALS